Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 87.
And this exercise, we are going to implement the graph data structure and job, so I will create a
Java program that is very similar to see.
So I will implement it in Java here and you can make it as in C compiler, but you can change that.
This is some syntax.
Things.
OK.
So what is the final solution that I need to get it in the output?
I need to from this program to draw for me or to create for me a graph that connects the notes together?
So the final solution that I'm going to work with and I will give an example of this is that graph the
the first node.
These are the nodes.
And.
This is five, this is due, this is four, and this is silly.
I need to connect one three one with two.
One was for.
Duel with four three was four and the three was five and four with five and two with five.
OK, I need to get a final result of this exercise to make this graph.
So are you ready guys to implement that graph data structure?
It is something something like complex, but trust me, you will be a master in graph after solving
this exercise.
So let's begin.
The first step is understanding that basic component of the graph class.
I have created a graph chart new Java class here called a graph.
OK, so let me.
Make it here public, let me create it here.
Public class graph.
Yeah.
So we have created this class and inside this class, the first step and the building blocks and the
building codes is that node and that edge.
So let's create that class edge and first step is creating the edge class at.
Here and this class will give us or will contain and the source and the destination between any points
between two points.
We have a an edge and this edge, if we go, it's a straight line.
If we are going to represent it, if we will say that it's sourced from the first point and its destination
to the second point, it's very simple in terms of logic.
So we have created the edge that contains the source and the destination as integer variable.
OK, no.
The second step is creating the number of vertices and at just number of vertices and edges and vertices
and edges.
OK.
This is the number of vertices and that edges.
It's very simple.
Know how many vertices and how many edges that we are going to create.
We need to create an array.
The third step, an array to store all their edges, all the edges.
OK.
So I will create an edge edge array called edges.
Or can I create it as edge?
OK.
I have created an array of objects called add edges.
This is why we have this goes navigate the previous declaration.
OK.
And edges only to create that edge.
Because we have created before.
First step, creating the edge that contains the source and destination.
The second step creating how many number of vertices and edges that we are going to create, and the
third step is storing all the edges in an array.
Now let's create that constructor.
The fourth step constructor, we start by creating a graph.
This new graph and you create a new graph.
You should specify the vertices and the edges.
OK, so this vertices is equal to vertices is how many vertices is and how many edges.
OK.
Very simple.
This is the constructor.
Now the fifth step is initializing.
Or we can.
We will continue with the constructor.
We are going to initialized the edge array.
So here the fifth step is initializing
the edge array since we have created.
And when we create a new graph and we insert there are diseases that just as numbers and we specify
them, we should create an array.
This is the array at in the same number of edges, so equal to new edge array of edges.
And.
Of the same number of the edges that we have best.
OK, so what we are going what we have created is creating a constructor of the craft that took into
parameter to the vertices and the edges, and then we have initialized the edge array with the past
30 meters edges.
OK, we specify how many edges and we create that at the array edge with fixed size of the past edges.
And we start looping through it and equal to zero I at less than just.
Because we need to pass through all the elements, all the edges.
And what we are going to do.
Each element of the array is an object of edge, though, so I need to specify here.
Let me tell you, because sometimes maybe confused.
So each element of the edge array is an object of its type, but it's very, very obvious that we are
creating an element of we are creating an array of edges.
So all the each element inside this edge array is an edge.
So edge.
At and I will be watching you at creating a new edge.
OK.
No, what we are going to specify.
We are going to specify that this thenation and the source for every edge that we have created, so
how to specify if we are going to go to there?
We are going to make a driver clad driver code that tests our code.
So public static void main.
This is the main and inside the main.
We can specify the connection.
So args here.
You look at the edge compared with the previously created data structures.
It is better, it is more complex with was the edge and the vertices and using the array and enclosing
that loop here in the constructor.
It may be sometimes confusing, but if you understand this, this exercise, it's very simple to make
and create an object of graph class and specify the edges, the notes and other.
So let's begin that
step number six here.
Creating graph object but we will create I will create and number offered diseases in the exercise I
would show you again.
You will tell me.
And number of edges.
Also, you will tell me so in the exercise in the beginning of this exercise, how many edges that we
have, we have one, two, three, four and five for diseases and how many edges we have.
One two three four, five, six, seven and eight.
We have eight edges, eight edges and five vertices.
OK, so this is our program that we are going to create this, our graph that we are going to create.
So please continue with me.
We have eight edges and we have five.
Vertices is OK now let's create the graph here.
Graph G equal to new new graph.
What we have, we have per two meters the end vertices and at just the number of vertices and the number
of edges I need to create.
Five vertices is and number of edges are eight.
OK, now
creating the edges between.
Let me show you again.
Between one and two, there is a connection between one and the city, there is a connection and between
one and four there is a connection.
Let me concentrate on one one connection in order to understand it.
And if you understand this connection between the one, the first node and the second.
No, no.
Number two, you will understand the other eight notes.
OK.
Connections.
So in order to create an edge between one and two, I will create Jib Dot agile.
Add at index zero, because we are storing it inside a
inside an array.
So what is the source of this?
What is the source of this at?
Edge between one and two, the source.
Is from one to two.
So this is the source and this is the destination.
OK.
This is the source, and this is the.
No.
The source is from want and need that edge at index zero.
The destination is going to vertex number two.
So this is the edge from one to two.
OK.
This is the edge, the edge from one to two.
OK, let me create the other edges between one and three.
OK.
The same.
I will copy this edge from one to three, from one to three.
The destination is one and the source is one and destination is three.
The edge would be the second edge and edge getting there.
OK.
Let me copy and paste it here.
The second edge, the second and next, which is the third edge.
From one to four.
OK, till now, I have four here.
One two, one two, one three and one for one.
Have any other connection?
No.
So I will go to number two.
OK.
Let me go two from two.
We have two one, we have created a previous year from one to two.
From two to four, we need to create a connection and from two to five, we need to create this connection.
So we have two connections to four and two five two two four.
Here will be the index.
Three, three, two and four.
And now create the AJA from two to five, which is deck the edge number five in the sequence from two
to five.
I need from you to understand the data structure here and how the edges work and how we connect it with
codes.
Now do we have finished at three?
Have was one.
We have talked about it.
We need to connect.
The city was four and three was five.
OK, so.
We paced front from three to four.
This is the and the next five from three to four.
And we need to create two from three to five.
Therefore, the edge here.
Six.
We have three to five.
OK.
No, we have created to create from four to five.
We have the edge here.
As seven.
From four to five.
OK.
Five, we have said two and five, we have said five and four, and we have five and three.
Everything is working fine.
So if we count these edges one, two, three, four, five, six and seven and eight, so here we go.
We are covering all the possibilities and all the edges.
OK.
Now, let's print that graph here.
The step number seven printing the graph.
Let's see how to print the graph for Int I equal to zero I less than number of edges and I + +.
I need to start printing and going through all the elements from zero to number of edges, which is
in the case, a about the print and.
I need to get G dot edges or edge at index, I thought source, I need the source of it.
Plus.
Minus, this is a dash plus G.
The edge.
Appendix, I thought this Dinesh Gay.
That's Iran and see this configuration, I need to Iran the main in the graph.
And here we go, we have eight connections.
Between one and two, between one and the three, we have connection one four two four two five.
Three, four, three, five and four five.
OK.
So congratulations, guys, we have implemented the graph data structure inside Java, and it's very
similar to see and I need from you to understand the basics, except the basics of the data structure
and how it works.
Then more.
We move to the syntax because syntax is not very important because we concentrate and the interviewer
will concentrate on the understanding of the data structure and the implementation, and that exam will
also.